# Rik L.E.M. Ubaghs

% rlemubaghs.com ♠ https://github.com/rlemubaghs ♥ Zurich, Switzerland 

#### Bio

I am a neural engineer specialized in neurotechnology. My areas of expertise are biomedical imaging, medical technology, brain-machine interfaces, and data analysis.

In my work, I am mostly interest in bridging the gab between experimental (neuro)technology and practical applications in the medical domain.

#### **Education**

ETH Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland

July 2017 - May 2023

Ph.D. Neurotechnology

University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, the Netherlands

Sept 2014 - June 2016

Research Master Brain and Cognitive Sciences, Cum Laude

Maastricht University, Maastricht, the Netherlands Bachelor Psychology and Neuroscience. Cum Laude

Sept 2011 - June 2014

## Skills

Languages: Dutch (Native), English (Fluent), German (Basic)

**Programming:** Python, Matlab, Rust, R, SQL

Skills: Microscopy, Industrial Design and Manufacturing, Biomedical Imaging

#### **Research Positions**

## AragoLabs (@Inst. of Neuroinformatics, ETH Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland)

June 2023 - Current

Co-founder

Development of a miniaturized microscope for tumor visualization and classification during neurosurgery.

### Institute of Neuroinformatics, ETH Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland

July 2017 – June 2023

Ph.D. Candidate

- Development of a MRI compatible florescence microscope (full-cycle product design).
- Design of a paradigm to combine microscopy and MR imaging methods in awake rodents.
- Design of data pipelines for multi-modal data analysis.

# Center for Neuroengineering, Duke University, Durham, USA

Dec 2015 - Nov 2016

Visiting Scientist

- Development of hybrid brain decoding methods in Non-human Primates.

## **Industry Positions**

### Agora Technology, Maastricht, The Netherlands

Nov 2016 - Feb 2018

Founder

- Built data solutions that aimed to streamline/automate the workflow within medical facilities, especially focussing on surgical equipment.
- Focused on logistics, and the creation, maintenance, and analysis of large-scale medical equipment databases using ML/DL.
- Clients included Maastricht University Medical Center and Medtronic.